Ludovica Tomaselli

- **(A)** +39 335 744 8213
- in linkedin.com/in/ludovicato
- github.com/ludovicato

Languages

- Italian
- English

Technical Skills

- Data cleaning
- Data visualization
- SQL
- Tableau
- Excel
- PowerPoint
- Python (numpy, pandas)
- R

Soft Skills

- Storytelling
- Creativity
- Communication
- Teamwork
- Curiosity

Profile

Data Analyst with experience in graphic design, video editing, and screenwriting, combining the best of two worlds to offer great data storytelling. Proficient in SQL, Excel, and Tableau, with the ability to extract insights and create visually engaging presentations. Creative, adaptable, and with a strong will to learn

Work experience

Data Analyst (Internship)

06/2022 - Present | Qwince | Palermo (Italy)

- Cleaned, prepped and analyzed a database in PostgreSQL and MySQL
- Worked on presentations using Looker Studio, PowerPoint and Photoshop
- Worked on video presentations using Babelee and After Effect

Data Analyst assignment

05/2022 | Smeralda Consulting | Palermo (Italy)

- Collected and analyzed information on tourism in the Madonie area in Sicily
- Developed a presentation on the subject with Looker Studio and PowerPoint

BigQuery Data Analyst (Internship)

12/2021 - 03/2022 | Cloudtec | Palermo (Italy)

- Successfully cleaned and recovered 70% of a previously unusable database filled with dirty data, utilizing SQL and BigQuery
- Analyzed the data and identified the main areas and hours of activity to streghten the company's presence where and when most necessary
- Built data visualization using Looker Studio

Graphic Designer and visitor assistant

09/2018 - 03/2021 | Santa Caterina Monastery Museum | Palermo (Italy)

- Created brochures, flyers, tickets, signs, images for socials and videos using Photoshop, Illustrator, Premiere and After Effect
- Created and administered the official websites using Wix
- Assisted the international visitors and escorted them in their visits

Freelance videoeditor and screenwriter

06/2009 - 09/2018 | in collaboration with Klexo group | Palermo (Italy)

- Worked as videoeditors on various music videos, short movies and short documentararies
- Worked on screenplay of various short movies, the outline and first volume of a comic and the outline and bible of two tv series
- Created a Youtube channel (Bleedgirl) that counts 130.000.000 views

Production assistant (Internship)

04/2013 - 09/2013 | Studiorain | Rome (Italy)

- Worked on the animated series "Everybody loves a Moose"
- Cohordinated the work between our studio and the production studio, closing a six week delay the production had previously accumulated

International experience

04/2012 - 09/2012 | Ashwell House | London (England)

- Worked as secretary | and part of administration team
- Improved my english while working in an international environment

Education

03/2021 - 03/2022 | II level Master in Data Science & Big Data Analytics EQF 8 | 95/100 (GPA 3.75) | University of Palermo | Palermo (Italy)

09/2011 - 03/2015 | **Master's degree in Cinema and Theatre** || EQF 7 *EQF 7 | 110/110 cum laude (GPA 4) | University of Palermo | Palermo (Italy)*

09/2006 - 03/2011 | **Bachelor in Art and Showbusiness** | EQF 6 *EQF 6* | *100/110 (GPA 3.55)* | *University of Palermo* | *Palermo (Italy)*

Certificates

12/2022 | Datacamp Data Analyst in SQL

02/2022 | Udemy Google Data Studio A-Z for Data Visualization

12/2021 | Coursera BigQuery Basics for Data Analysts